azfcu.org 2008-12-17

# Arizona Federal - Privacy Policy

We know that when it comes to your personal financial information, privacy is of the utmost importance. That’s why we always respect your privacy by adhering to a strict privacy policy. But more than just telling you this, it’s important that you know specifically what we’re doing to keep our promise to you. At Arizona Federal, service means that we handle your personal financial information with care. 

## General Definitions. 

The words "you" and "your(s)" mean every person that signs any Account Application or is authorized to make transactions regarding your account(s), including any account service(s). "We," "us," or "our" means the credit union. 

## We respect the trust you place in us.

At Arizona Federal we recognize that our relationships with our members are based on trust. As a member, you trust us with your financial and other personal information, and we are committed to respecting your privacy and safeguarding that information. We pledge to protect your privacy by adhering to the practices described in this section.

### 1\. The Types of Information We Collect.

We only collect information about our members for lawful business purposes, or as otherwise required by applicable law. 

We collect information about members from the following sources: (a) Applications for services, other forms and any communications you send to us including electronic messages from which we collect your name, addresses, phone numbers, social security numbers, financial data, birth date, gender and other information; (b) Transactions involving your accounts or services with us from which we collect information such as your name, account number, balance, payment history, parties to your transactions and credit card usage; (c) Consumer Credit Reports from which we collect information regarding your creditworthiness, credit history and account activity; and (d) Market Research Firms that provide us with a variety of information regarding our members such as the number of individuals in a household, home ownership, etc. 

You agree that the telephone numbers, street and email addresses provided in your Membership Application and Signature Card, or any other application or communication sent to us, are publicly available and will be used to provide notices, disclosures, statements, other communications (including but not limited to our responses to your email communications) and offers for certain products or services.

Arizona Federal’s Website. Use of our web site or linking to a site we sponsor requires the use of “cookies,” which are small pieces of information a website stores on a visitor’s web browser to remind the site about the user the next time the site is visited. We do not store confidential or sensitive information through the use of cookies. Our use of cookies enhances our member’s online transactions and eases navigation through our website. For certain applications, such as online transactions, cookies are required to help protect the privacy of a member’s transactions by, for example, terminating the session if the member forgets to log out. We collect email addresses from members who request electronic services, and from users of our website who choose to provide their addresses. We do not disclose cookie information to nonaffiliated third parties.

### 2\. The Types of Information We Disclose.

We do not disclose any non-public personal information about our members or former members except as permitted by applicable law. To benefit our members, we share the information described in Paragraph 1 within the credit union, and with certain trusted third parties described in this paragraph, who are obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of your private information. We use the services of various third parties to assist us in offering financial services to our members. For example, we use the services of third parties for processing transactions using credit cards, checks, check cards, ATM cards and other access devices; for assistance in making loans, loan underwriting; processing loan applications; for appraising collateral and for processing our outgoing mail. We also work with companies that provide financial planning, investment services, extended automotive service contracts, personal and property insurance, credit counseling and retail automobile sales to members. 

_Fair and Accurate Credit Transactions Act:_ The credit union may report information about your account(s) to third parties such as credit reporting agencies/bureaus. Late payments, missed payments, insufficient funds transactions or other defaults on your loan and share/share draft account(s) may be reflected in your credit report.  
We share information with our affiliates, Western States Financial Group, LLC and Arizona Federal Insurance Solutions, LLC. 

### 3\. Security. 

We are committed to taking every reasonable precaution to protect individual identifying information that you provide to us. We share non-public personal information about you only with employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We also maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to guard your non-public personal information. 

### 4\. Notices and Joint Relationships.

Except where expressly required by applicable law, we will provide all notices to the person (member) listed first on any application, agreement or other relevant document with us. The notice will be mailed to the address noted for said person on the application, agreement or other document. If this person (member) has agreed to receive notices and disclosures electronically, then we can send all such notices and notifications to the email or Internet address provided by said person. All joint owners, borrowers and guarantors agree to the receipt and sufficiency of any notice or notification sent according to this paragraph.

### 5\. Modification.

The credit union reserves the right to modify, change or amend this Privacy Policy and Agreement at any time without notice other than as expressly required by applicable law.

### 6\. What Members Can Do To Help.

Protect your account numbers, card numbers, PINs (personal identification numbers) and passwords. In particular, never keep your PIN with your debit card or credit card, as that makes you vulnerable in the event you lose your card or your card is stolen. Use caution in revealing account numbers, social security numbers, etc. to other persons. In particular, if a caller tells you he/she is calling you on behalf of the credit union and asks for your account number, you should beware. Legitimate credit union staff would already have access to that information. It’s important that the credit union has current information about how to reach you. If we detect potentially fraudulent use of your account, we will attempt to contact you immediately. If your address or phone number changes, please let us know.

### 7\. Protecting Children.

We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children and we do not knowingly market to children online. We recognize that protecting children’s identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents.

###  8\. Beware of Phishing Scams.

“Phishing” scams are official-looking email that appear to have come from your credit union, bank, credit card company, etc. These email messages usually state something is wrong with your account, and request you to verify your private and confidential information. These messages are fraudulent. We will not contact you by email with a request to verify your information or to inform you that you have a problem with your account. You should delete any such emails — never reply to them and never follow their instructions. 

Back to top ››
